Guide to the Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning 1969-2005 Collection, 1969-2005
Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning 1969-2005 Collection, 1969-2005
- Series III. Berkeley, California
  - Berkeley Key Documents. Compiled by Pierre Clavel and Sharon Lord., July 1, 1989
    - "BCA: Does Everyone Have Access?." The Daily Californian., Nov. 14, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 19)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 4 pages. -- Author: Miner, Will and Howard Levine.
    - "Berkeley Government at Turning Point." The Daily Californian., Nov. 15, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Swimming Against Tide: Sometimes It's Natural." New York Times., Sept. 30, 1987. (Box 10, Folder 19)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 1 pages. -- Author: Reinhold, Robert.
  - City of Berkeley, Comprehensive Planning Department. Summary of Berkeley's Economy and Proposals for Economic Planning., Oct. 1, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - The Berkeley Business Incentive Program: An Analysis of Organizational Structure and Process. Institute of Urban and Regional Development. University of California, Berkeley., June 1, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    Original Publication. 21 pages. -- Author: Sussman, Paul and Joyce Klemperer.
  - Mike to OED Staff RE: OED Staff Meeting Discussion August 4, 1987. "Economic Development, West Berkeley and Jobs: Target Manufacturing Sectors and Options for Employment Linkage Strategies.", Aug. 4, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    Photocopy. 37 pages. -- Author: Squire, Kate and Mike Alison.
  - Economic Development: An Implementation Strategy for the City of Berkeley. Institute of Urban and Regional Development. University of California, Berkeley. Working Paper No. 354, June 1, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    Original Publication. 34 pages. -- Author: Weiss, Marc Allan ad Ann Roell Markusen.
  - Interviews
    - Bach, Eve. Interview., Sept. 12, 1991. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Newport, Gus. Interviewed by Marie Kennedy., Feb. 6, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Mayer, Neil. Interview., Sept. 12, 1991. (Box 10, Folder 24)
      Photocopy. 36 pages.
    - Fukson, Veronika. Interview: Second Session., July 16, 1981. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Compilation of Papers form Berkeley Economic Development Project Group. Institute of Urban and Regional Development. University of California Berkeley., 1981
    Photocopies. 2 pages.
    - Economic Development: An Implementation Strategy for the City of Berkeley. Working Paper No. 354., June 1, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Photocopy. 32 pages. -- Author: Weiss, Marc Allan and Ann Roell Markusen.
    - The Berkeley Business Incentive Program: An Analysis of Organizational Structure and Process., June 1981. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Photocopy. 22 pages. -- Author: Sussman, Paul and Joyce Klemperer.
    - Job Creation in the Family Service Sector: The Case of Child Care. Working Paper No. 356., June 1981. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Photocopy. 14 pages. -- Author: Markusen, Ann and Marjorie Bennett.
    - The Berkeley Economy: The Prospects for Economic Development Planning. Working Paper No. 355., Apr. 1981. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Photocopy. 50 pages. -- Author: Markusen, Ann, Jay Jones, Nancey Leigh-Preston and Neil Mayer.
    - Creating Jobs in Berkeley by Alternative Energy Strategies., June 1981. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Photocopy. 22 pages. -- Author: Skewes-Cox, Amy.
  - "Slouching towards Berkeley: Socialism in One City." The Public Interest. p. 47-68. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    Photocopy. 11 pages. -- Author: Collier, Peter and David Horowitz.
  - Keating, et al. BTOC Analysis of Rent Control Demands. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    Typescript. 21 pages.
  - Berkeley Contacts (Box 10, Folder 28)
    Handwritten. 3 pages.
  - Memorandum: Progress of the Office of Economic Development at One Year Anniversary. To Honorable Mayor and Members of the City Council. From Hal Cronkite, Acting City Manager., Oct. 20, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    Photocopy. 5 pages. -- Author: Cronkite, Hal.
  - Memorandum: Council Discussion on the Economic Development Plan. To Wise Allen, City Manager. From David Romain, Economic Development Specialist. With attachment: Economic Development Plan, City of Berkeley, Policy Summary., Sept. 12, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    Photocopy. 18 pages. -- Author: Romain, David.
  - Memorandum: Recommendations on Budget and Future of the Planning Department. To Wise E. Allen, City Manager. From Fred Collignon, Chairperson., Feb. 4, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 6 pages. -- Author: Collignon,, Fred.
  - Reforming Progressive Government. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    Photocopy. 12 pages. -- Author: Collignon, Frederick.
  - "Union-Management Partnerships." CPER 125. p. 14-18., Aug. 1997 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    Photocopy. 5 pages. -- Author: Barton, Stephen.
  - City of Berkeley, Planning & Development Department. Rent Control in the City of Berkeley, 1978 to 1994: A Background Report., May 17, 1998 (Box 10)
    Original. 200 pages.
  - Berkeley Documents and Unpublished Papers. Compiled by Pierre Clavel. (Box 10)
    - "Running the City for the People." p. 15-23., Winter 1982 (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 3 pages. -- Author: Bach, Eve, Nicholas R. Carbone, and Pierre Clavel.
    - An Analysis: The Economic Development Process in Berkeley, California. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 21 pages. -- Author: Aamot, Jacqueline.
    - Berkeley Tenants Organizing Committee and Community Rent Control Slate. "Platform of the Community Rent Control Convention.", Apr. 17, 1973. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 4 pages.
    - Memo. To Mayor and Members of the City Council. From Hal Cronkite, Acting City Manager. Re: Progress of the Office of Economic Development at One Year Anniversary., Oct. 20, 1986 (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 5 pages. -- Author: Cronkite, Hal.
    - Neighborhood Preservation Ordinance. No. 4641, Apr. 17, 1973. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 3 pages.
    - Kirschner, Ed. Interview. Transcript, Oct., 1981 (Box 10)
    - Memo. To Wise E. Allen, City Manager. From Fred Collignon, Chairperson. Re: Recommendations on Budget and Future of the Planning Department., Feb. 4, 1981. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 3 pages. -- Author: Collignon, Fred
    - Kirschner, Ed. Lecture at Cornell University. Transcript., Oct. 2, 1981 (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 6 pages. -- Author: Kirschner, Ed
    - Ordinance. City of Berkeley. Prohibiting Rent Gouging and Unfair Rental Practices and Promoting an Adequate Supply of Housing for all Residents. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 7 pages.
    - Memo. To Mayor and Members of the City Council. From Councilmembers Shirley Dean, Sue Hone and Bill Segesta., Jan. 29, 1980 (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 1 page. -- Author: Dean, Shirly, Sue Hone, and Bill Segesta
    - A Survey of Housing in Berkeley: Analyzing Three Issues. University of California, Berkeley., Nov. 1, 1980 (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 35 pages. -- Author: Falk, Don, Diane Laufman, Livinus Nwadike and Nancy Southerland.
    - The Berkeley Economy: The Prospects for Economic Development Planning. Working Paper No. 355., Apr. 1981. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 50 pages. -- Author: Markusen, Ann, Jay Jones, Nancey Leigh-Preston and Neil Mayer.
    - Job Creation in the Family Service Sector: The Case of Child Care. Working Paper No. 356., June 1981. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 14 pages. -- Author: Markusen, Ann and Marjorie Bennett.
    - Creating Jobs in Berkeley by Alternative Energy Strategies., June 1981. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 22 pages. -- Author: Skewes-Cox, Amy.
    - Memo. To OED Staff. From Kate Squire and Mike Alison. Re OED Staff Meeting Discussion, August 4, 1987. Economic Development, West Berkeley and Jobs: Target Manufacturing Sectors and Options for Employment Linkage Strategies. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 10 pages. -- Author: Squire, Kate and Mike Alison.
    - Business Relocation Survey - July, 1987. Conducted by Michael Allison. Office of Economic Development, City of Berkeley. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 10 pages.
    - Memo. To Neil Mayer. From Kate Squire. Re Staffing Employment Coordination. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 3 pages. -- Author: Squire, Kate
    - Economic Development: An Implementation Strategy for the City of Berkeley. Working Paper No. 354., June 1, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Fair Representation Ordinance. No. 4780 (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 1 page.
    - Interviewed by Pierre Clavel. Transcript., Apr. 16, 1989. (Box 10)
      Copy in Bound Publication. 21 pages. -- Author: Bach, Eve.
  - Volume 1. Selected Newspaper Articles, Berkeley. Compiled by Pierre Clavel and others from California Journal, Daily Californian, East Bay Express, Grassroots, Los Angeles Times, San Francisco Chronicle, and Urban Care. 1969-1985. 120 pieces, 1969-1985 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    Photocopies. Original Newsprint.
    - "For Every Hotel Room, a Valentine." The New York Times., Feb. 14, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 1 page. -- Author: Bishop, Katherine.
    - "Political Party May Blossom - then winter." The Daily Californian., Dec. 11, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Berkeley: A 'zone of control'." The Guardian., Oct. 2, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 2 pages. -- Author: Kelley, Kevin J.
    - "Fall Elections: Changing of the Guard?" The Daily Californian., Sept. 12, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Boot, Max.
    - "Ambivalent Electorate Firmly Says 'No' to Oil." Los Angeles Times., Nov. 6, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Stein, Mark A.
    - "Progressives in Berkeley Challenged by Tradition." Los Angeles Times., Nov. 3, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Stein, Mark A.
    - "Berkeley gets a new breed of left-leaning." The Philadelphia Inquirer., Dec. 21, 1984. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Berkeley Vote Results Baffling, As Usual." San Francisco Chronicle., Nov. 5, 1998. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Burress, Charles.
    - "Low Voter Turnout Helped Measure C win." The Daily Californian., June 11, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 3 pages. -- Author: Friedman, Phillip.
    - "Forgotten Man: A Parting Look at the Life and Times of Berkeley mayor Gus Newport." Express., Nov. 7, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 2 pages. -- Author: Friedman, Phillip.
    - "Newport is first in BCA line for Mayor." The Daily Californian., Feb. 12, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 2 pages. -- Author: Rexroat, Nikki.
    - "Should Berkeley switch to district Elections?" The Daily Californian., Mar. 18, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 1 page. -- Author: Skinner, Nancy.
    - "BCA convention gives Hancock nod for Mayor." The Daily Californian. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 2 pages. -- Author: Anderson, Craig.
    - "Candidates' Questionnaire." League of Women Voters of Berkeley., May 26, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Newsprint. 1 page.
    - "Peace - Not Poverty." Community for New Politics. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - City of Berkeley. Special Municipal Elections: Consolidated with the Consolidated Primary Elections. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Pamphlet. 6 pages.
    - Scheer for Congress - Draft Platform. Robert Scheer for Congress: Berkeley, CA. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Platform of the Community Rent Control Convention., Jan., 1973. (Box 10, Folder 34)
      Original Pamphlet. 4 pages.
  - "Berkeley City Council." Bay Guardian., Oct. 26, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Stallone, Steve. Bay Guardian Articles.
    - "BCA Runs from the 'R-C' Words." p. 15., Nov. 23, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 36)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Stallone, Steve.
    - "Confrontation Looms in Berkeley Over Police Removal of Homeless Collective." p. 9., Mar. 16, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 36)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Stallone, Steve.
    - "Berkeley's Low-Cost Housing Breakthrough." 23 (20)., Feb. 22, 1989. (Box 10, Folder 36)
      Photocopy. 4 pages. -- Author: Stallone, Steve.
  - "The 'Respectable Radicals' and the Politics of Berkeley." California Journal. Vol. 12., Apr. 1981. (Box 10, Folder 37)
    Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Westcott, John.
  - Berkeley Citizens Action (BCA) Chronology and Newspaper Clippings. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Berkeley Chronology and List of Acknowledgements.. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Second Thoughts: BCA and the Politics of Moderation." Express. 8 (45)., Aug. 15, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 8 pages. -- Author: McGrath, Mike.
    - "BCA snubs Fukson, she bows out of race.", July 28, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: De Wolk, Roland.
    - "Has the Left Delivered?" Express 2 (41)., Aug. 8, 1980. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Goldberg, Art.
    - "Liberal City Politics Born in '50s Struggle." The Daily Californian., May 8, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Newdorf, David.
    - "Semi-Official Election Results." The Daily Californian 23 (56), Nov. 10, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1page.
    - "Affordable Housing Hits West Berkeley Area." The Daily Californian., Nov. 7, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1page. -- Author: Navos, Jose.
    - "Skinner fights Bright, Sanford." The Daily Californian., Nov. 7, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1page. -- Author: Anderson, Craig.
    - "Berkeley City Council and City Measures Results." The Daily Californian., Nov. 3, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Progressive Regressions, Regressive Progressives." The Daily Californian., Nov. 3, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Herron, Jim.
    - "City's balance of power hinges on districts 7, 5, 2." The Daily Californian., Nov. 3, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Herron, Jim.
    - "Future of Berkeley Rent Control Laws up for Grabs as Rival Slates Seek Power Over Board." The Daily Californian., Nov. 1, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "BCA group ask Mayor to Renounce No-on-J Ties." The Daily Califronian 23 (49)., Nov. 1, 1988. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 3 pages. -- Author: Webster, Katharine.
    - "March splits with BCA on historically low rent." The Daily Californian., Feb. 14, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Freeman, Michael.
    - "State Court Dilutes Rent Control." The Daily Californian 25 (75)., May 3, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Mayor faces four ballot challengers." The Daily Californian., Aug. 15, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Ghori, Imran.
    - "Stakes High in Rent Board Race." The Daily Californian. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Ghori, Imran.
    - "Candidates for School Board Differ on Restructuring." The Daily California., Aug. 21, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Rent Control on my Mind." (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Hill, Brian.
    - "City Council Candidates Battle it out." The Daily Californian., Oct. 5, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Jennings, Ralph.
    - "Rent board, not Measure E should tackle rent control law." The Daily Californian. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Goldberg, Art.
    - "Measure E is not a remedy for Berkeley's rent Control." The Daily Californian. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Chanler, Ann.
    - "CFRC tops BCA candidates in the battle for rent board." (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Schindler, Todd.
    - "Weekes, Hancock slug it out in mayoral race homestretch." The Daily Californian., Oct. 24, 1990. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Finseth, Ian.
    - "City to consolidate citizen commissions." The Daily Californian. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Grabel, Katy.
    - "City Elections '86: November Vote, BCA on Trial." The Daily Californian., Oct. 6, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "District Elections to stay." The Daily Californian 24 (57)., Nov. 5, 1986. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "City Election were Hot and Spicy." The Daily Californian. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Roddy, Jane E.
    - "BA may lose council majority." The Daily Californian 26 (165)., Nov. 4, 1992. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      2 copies. Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Roddy, Jane E. and Noah Berger.
    - "City Council, School Board, Rent Board." The Daily Californian., Oct. 27, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Rent Board Faces a Shift in Power." The Daily Californian., Nov. 5, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Lee, Katrina J.
    - "Berkeley to Grapple with Tough Issues.", Nov. 15, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Suan, Tara.
    - "Mayoral Race Coming to an End.", Nov. 8, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Election Endorsements.", Nov. 4, 1994. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "1994 Election Supplement - Part One." (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Four Votes, All the Difference.", Nov. 6, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Zazueta, Rob.
    - "Woodworth Makes a Bid to Keep Her City Council Seat.", Oct. 31, 1996. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "The Race for City Council - District 7", Oct. 24, 1996. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Woodworth, Carla, Kriss Worthington and Sheila Holderness.
    - "Progressive Politics to Dominate City.", Nov. 7, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Council Seats Breakdown: 1986-1996. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Typescript. 2 pages.
    - "Citywide. Primary Reeducation: On the Trail with BCA." Express, May 7, 1982. (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: McGrath, Mike.
  - Grassroots Articles: 1974-1981, Neighborhood Focus, Plan Focus. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Berkeley - What's Next?", Dec. 18, 1974-Jan. 7, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "BCA: Coalition Hammers Out Platform.", Jan. 22 - Feb. 4, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Citizens' Group Names Slate at Public Convention.", Feb. 5-18, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Berkeley - What's Next?", Feb. 20, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Dellums Raps on Berkeley Politics.", Apr. 23-May 6, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Drive for Rent Control - Leash Law for Landlords.", Mar. 26-Apr. 8, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "An Interview with Margot Dashiell.", May 7-20, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "BCA shows percentage gain.", May 21-June 2, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
      Photocopy. 3 pages. -- Author: Mundstock, David.
    - "Citizen's Action Group Reads Between the Elections.", June 4-June 17, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Florence McDonald: New Auditor Stresses Availability, Visibility.", Aug. 6-19, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Tenants Screwed Again: Council machine Grinds On.", Nov. 19-Dec. 9, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Economic Development Left to 'Experts'.", Dec. 10-23, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "BCA's Plans for Berkeley.", Apr. 9-23, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Economic Survey: Businessmen Cry Wolf.", Dec. 24-Jan. 13, 1976. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Plan for Berkeley Future Growth." (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "City Council Votes $19,000 to BTOC.", Mar. 24-Apr. 6, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Court, Legislature Flatten Tenants.", June 23-July 6, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Tenants Organize for New Laws.", Nov. 17-Dec. 7, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Rent Control Petition Circulates.", Dec. 27-Jan. 11, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Questions and Answers on.", Mar. 9-22, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Tenant-Landlord Bargaining Law.", Mar. 23-Apr. 6, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "State Rent Control Study Gives Lie to Landlord Claims.", Apr. 6-26, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Santa Fe Tracks Derail new Park Program", Apr. 6-26, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Council May Force Rent Relief Ordinance to Court.", Aug. 16-Sept. 5, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Here's How Measure 'I' Works.", Nov. 22-Dec. 5, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "City Rejects University Deaf-Blind School Plan.", June 6-19, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Master Plan Confusing, Incomplete Argues Kent.", Feb. 25-Mar. 9, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "PRC, City Manager Confer on Power.", May 5-18, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Council of Neighborhood Associations A Forum for Community Issues.", Nov. 1-21, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Neighborhoods Organizing.", July 1, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Ten Years of Tenants Organizing.", Nov. 7-20, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Author Speaks Out ON City Finances, Operations.", June 14-27, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Loni Hancock on the Election: The Issues and a New Majority.", Apr. 6-25, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Left Shows Gains - Berkeley Elections.", Aug. 4-17 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Veronika Fukson.", Mar. 9-22, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Margot Dashiell's Agenda: Jobs and Rent Control.", Mar. 23-Apr. 6, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Kelly works for a Progressive Berkeley.", Apr. 6-26, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Call for Unity Against Landlords.", Dec. 5-18, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Bankroll Flattens Left.", May 11-24, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Santa Fe Track Plans.", Nov. 9-22, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Berkeley Tenants Union: 'Organize!'.", Sept. 14-27, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "BCA Talking on Several Issues.", Nov. 9-22, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Group for Labor-Progressive Ties.", May 3-23, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "BCA: No Position on Barsotti Recall." (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Berkeley Citizens Action Turns Right.", Oct. 4-18, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "April is the Cruelest Month.", Dec. 20, 1978 - Jan. 9, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Berkeley Demo Alliance Divided on Direction.", Jan. 24-Feb. 6, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Florence McDonald.", Apr. 4-24, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Whose Left?", Oct. 18-Nov. 3 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Doomsayers Lose Budget Battle.", Aug. 8-21, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Left Wins Big in Berkeley.", June 2, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Community Services - Hassles and Hopes.", Mar. 21-Apr. 8, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Activist Will Strengthen Tenants' Rights.", Mar. 25, Apr. 7, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Behind the Berkeley Tenant Controversy.", July 15-28, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 39)
      2 copies. Original Newsprint. 4 pages.
    - Neighborhood Focus (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Neighborhood Fights City for Park.", July 1, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Neighborhood Councils - Who Draws the Lines?", Nov. 21-Dec. 4, 1973. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Council Majority Stalls on Savo Island Redevelopment.", Mar. 26-Apr. 8, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Time Running Out for Oceanview?", Dec. 18-Januar 7, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Council Approves Savo Island Project, Taylor's Revenue Sharing Plan.", Apr. 9-23, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Savo Island Breaks Ground!", Dec. 20-Jan. 9, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Industrial Group Harasses Denton.", Dec. 10-23, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "How can we miss it when it won't go away?", Aug. 19-Sept. 1, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Redevelopment Robs from Poor, Gives to Rich.", Jan. 28-Dec. 10, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Plan Focus (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Public Hearing on Housing.", Dec. 10-23, 1975. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "For City Council: John Denton, Veronika Fukson.", Apr. 4-24, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "BCA's Divided Convention Gives Way To Harmony.", Jan. 24-Feb. 6, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "Neighborhood organizes against Land Grab.", Oct. 29-Nov. 7, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 39)